Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Fournet, Adele, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5886; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  The website contains a short biography of the artist, a list of texts and scores, documentary, music and composition videos, and audio files. Fournet is a musician, producer, video artist, and composer, who has been involved as a percussionist, vocalist, and keyboard player in several ensembles. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
  Adele Fournet Papers (MSS 516)
- Fried, Joshua, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5846; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://joshuafried.com/, http://composer.home.acedsl.com/ and http://radiowonderland.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These sites are http://composer.home.acedsl.com/ and http://radiowonderland.org/.
  The website contains a brief biography of the artist and several of his projects, and an embedded audio file. Fried's works incorporate non-traditional instruments such as shoes and steering wheels with commercial FM radio and various musical technologies to create recombinant funk music. Radio Wonderland is the solo project of Joshua Fried. The website contains links to videos, recent and upcoming show listings, blog posts, a biography of Joshua Fried, and information on his album, Seize the Means. Capture of the website began in June 2017.
- Frucht, Paul, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5892; 2 websites in 2 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.paulfrucht.com/ and https://www.paulfruchtmusic.com/
  in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Crawl was expanded to include soundcloud.
  The website contains a list of works by Frucht, a calendar of the artist's events, articles relating to Frucht and his works, as well as 1 audio file and 3 embedded video files that were not captured. His musical works are composed for traditional instruments and have been played by many different chamber and orchestral groups. Frucht is also involved in several music education groups such as the Western Connecticut Youth Orchestra and the Danbury Chamber Music Intensive, which seek to educate musicians through training and performance. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Fullman, Ellen, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5872; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ellenfullman.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  It contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of her events, her discography, images of the artist and of the instruments she builds, and articles relating to Fullman and her work. Her main musical focus is exploring the acoustics of large resonant spaces through her installation, The Long String Instrument. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Fulmer, David, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5921; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://fulmermusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, news and press related to his music, list of his work, including chamber, electronics, orchestral, solo, and vocal compositions, a calendar of past and upcoming events, discography, and contact information. Fulmer is a composer and violinist. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Fure, Ash, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Ash Fure (b. 1982) is an American composer and sonic artist that blends performance and installation. The website contains her CV, descriptions of her scores and installations, and audio files. In 2020, the website had a new URL and refomatting containing videos of performances, music videos, and press listings.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ashleyfure.com and ashleyfure.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Galas, Diamanda, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5867; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://diamandagalas.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website details her work as a vocal performer as well as her writings and art. The site contains images of the artist and of her artistic works. Her music and art explore the ways in which poetry, visual media, and music can be brought together to convey profound concepts. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Gann, Kyle, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.kylegann.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a list of composer and musicologist Kyle Gann's compositions, a discography of his published musical works, examples of his prose writings, information about the books he's written, PDFs of his scores, and images of the artist. Gann's website highlights his microtonal instrumental music and time spent as a new-music critic for the Village Voice. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Gardner, Alexandra, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5866; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.alexandragardner.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works, upcoming and past events, discography, press articles related to her music, and contact information. Gardner's music mixes acoustic instruments with electronics while drawing inspiration from mythology, poetry, and her training in percussion. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Ghys, Florent, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://florentghys.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image and Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Certain aspects of the site layout do not render correctly in the archived site due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a double bassist, guitarist, vocalist, and composer of music which he performs both solo and with his music group, Bonjour. His works make use of electronic and acoustic instruments. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
  Bonjour (Musical group)
- Gibson, John, March 2020-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  John Gibson composes acoustic and electroacoustic music that has been performed worldwide. He seeks to complement and extend the musical inflections of performers with electronic sound, sometimes generated in real time by the software he develops. His music embraces influences ranging from contemporary classical to jazz, funk, and electronica. The website contains recording information, composition audio and descriptions, software projects, and his writings.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of john-gibson.com and johgibso.pages.iu.edu in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Gibson, Randy, July 2017- ongoing; cuid5931; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.randy-gibson.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information on projects, news related to his music, list of works, discography, press articles, picture gallery, contact information, and a calendar of his events. Gibson's music explores the experience of time and the senses using intonation combined with live performers and live or pre-recorded sound, as well as visual aspects. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Gilliam, Daniel, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5903; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://danielgilliam.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, audio that can be listened to, bought, or shared, videos, online store, and a link to his Tumblr blog. Gilliam composes music that is inspired by his life and other musicians. Gilliam composes for orchestras as well as smaller instrumental ensembles. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Gisburg, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5922; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://gisburg.info/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works, including compositions and soundtracks, news related to her music, her teaching resume, and a videos and trailers page. Gisburg is a singer and composer who has produced pieces for film and theater. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Glatthorn, Dylan, February 2014- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://dylanglatthorn.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded video and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files, a discography of his published albums, and news about Glatthorn. The website contains music from his work on scores from TV and film as well as musical theater and concerts. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site. Also includes the promotional website for the musical "Edison" with music and lyrics by composer Dylan Glatthorn which sets to music the life and history of American inventor Thomas Edison. The site features biographies of Glatthorn and bookwriter Will Lacker, a synopsis of the show, and an embedded soundcloud playlist featuring songs from the show. The site was first captured in February 2020. This description is based on the February 2020 capture of the site.
- Goldstein, Malcolm, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5877; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.philmultic.com/artists/goldstein/index.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of Goldstein, a calendar of his events, his discography, reviews of his works, and a description of his collaboration with Liu Fang, another musician. Goldstein is a violinist as well as a composer, and has been involved in several musical ensembles as well as doing work as a solo artist. Many of his works incorporate improvisation and unusual performance techniques. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Goode, Daniel, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5943; 4 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://danielgoode.com/, gamelan.org, gamelansonoflion.org and deliberatelyconsidered.com/2011/09/against-cliches-about-mahlers-music/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These sites are gamelan.org, gamelansonoflion.org and deliberatelyconsidered.com/2011/09/against-cliches-about-mahlers-music/.
  The website contains 41 embedded audio files and 8 embedded video files of recordings of his works, descriptions and reviews of his compositions, a discography, a calendar of his events, image files of the artist and his scores, and 21 works of prose by Goode. Goode is a composer and clarinetist with influences ranging from bird song to to Indonesian gamelan music who uses circular breathing techniques to create his characteristic sound. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Gordon, Michael, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://michaelgordonmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, press relating to Gordon and his music, and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files and prose pieces. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of orchestral works as well as chamber pieces making use of electronic tools to modify the sounds of traditional instruments. He is also a noted performer on the electronic keyboard and the founder of the Michael Gordon Philharmonic. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
  Michael Gordon Philharmonic
- Gosfield, Annie, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5914; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.anniegosfield.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a discography of her works with information about the pieces, a calendar of her events, images of the artist, reviews of Gosfield and her work, and examples of her prose writings. Gosfield incorporates improvisation into scored pieces, utilizing both electric and acoustic instruments to create compositions that balance noise with music. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Green, Edward, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5923; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.edgreenmusic.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information on current projects, list of publications and compositions, and external links. Green's compositions include chamber ensembles, chorus, symphony orchestra, solos, music for film, and the theater. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Greenstein, Judd, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.juddgreenstein.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files, information about his projects, and a calendar of his events. The music pieces featured on the website are primarily post-genre and orchestral instrumental works for ensembles and soloists. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Grimes, Rachel, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.rachelgrimespiano.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files, information about her projects, news about Grimes, and a calendar of her events. The website highlights Grimes' work as a touring pianist, rock and indie-rock group member, and composer of instrumental works for chamber and orchestral ensembles. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Haber, Yotam, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.yotamhaber.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio files do not function on the live site or in the capture.
  The website contains a biography of the composer and pianist Yotam Haber, his Curriculum Vitae, a calendar of his events, press pieces written about Haber, information about his compositions, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site are classically-inspired instrumental chamber pieces. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Hallman, Joseph, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.josephhallman.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played. Embedded Soundcloud audio files were not captured.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his discography of published albums, scores for his compositions, excerpts from articles and reviews written about Hallman, and examples of his compositions in the form of embedded audio files. The pieces featured on the site are chamber music, classically-influenced instrumental compositions for ensembles and solo performers. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Harrison, Michael, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5924; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.michaelharrison.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, press articles regarding his music, an online store, photo gallery, links, contact information, and a calendar of his events. Harrison specializes in just intonations and Indian ragas, and plays the piano. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Hearne, Ted, February 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.tedhearne.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images, video and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
- Hemingway, Gerry, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5925; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.gerryhemingway.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, news regarding his work, discography, press articles, videos of his performances, mp3 files, links and articles of interest, and contact information. Hemingway is a percussionist, composer, soloist, collaborator, and ensemble member. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Hernandez, Katt, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://sites.google.com/site/katthernandez/home in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Hersch, Michael, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5926; 2 websites in 2 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.michaelhersch.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, news regarding his work, list of upcoming and past concerts, videos and audio files, press articles, discography, and contact information. Hersch's compositions range from solos to chamber music, and he is a gifted pianist. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
  Also includes website for Michael Hersch's "I hope we get a chance to visit soon." The work, a companion piece to his 2012 monodrama On the Threshold of Winter, revisits several themes Hersch has engaged with often over the past decade, terminal illness and loss.
- Higdon, Jennifer, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5927; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.jenniferhigdon.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works and recordings, reviews of her work, information on upcoming performances, and contact information. Higdon's compositions include orchestral, chamber, choral, vocal, and wind ensemble. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Hirsch, Shelley, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5885; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.shelleyhirsch.com/shelley/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  This is the archived website of Shelley Hirsch, a singer, performer, and composer active in New York's Downtown scene and internationally since the 1980's. She has done extensive solo work as well as collaborations on musical and multimedia works. The website contains a brief biography of the musician, excerpts from reviews of her work, a list of her events, and links to videos of her performances. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.